Steffen Riber Thomsen

Network & Computer Engineer

Profesional Profile



I am an ambitious and recently graduated Computer Engineer with specialization in Network and Distributed Systems. I have a great passion for analyzing and developing tailored solutions for complex systems. My drive stems from the ability to keep a great overview of the problems and realize solutions using the latest technology.

Contact Details

- Solimanvej 4 2770 Kastrup Denmark
- (+45) 22 27 90 14
- riber4@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/steffenriber

• Date of Birth: March 18th 1987 • Civil Status: Married • Nationality: Danish

Work Experiences

Software Engineer at Naviair

09/2021 -

I worked as a swiss army knife at Naviair, where I took on the responsibility as a Software Lead helping my team grow as a unit and write better solutions. A Product Owner helping planning and scoping projects with our Business Management. A Software and Cloud Architect with focus on DevOps and CI/CD structure.

Lead Software Engineer at Terma A/S

04/2018 - 09/2021

I was put as responsible lead for the Product team whose main focus was to revamp the Combat Management System (C-Flex) to a easier accessible system that is minded towards Patrol and light vessels and their missions. My work included leading the team towards its goals, and improving its overall quality as a software team. This included requirement analysis, technical research, system and software design.

Software Engineer at Terma A/S

10/2014 - 04/2018

My work included developing new features, maintaining and improving the Combat Management System (C-Flex) for the Royal Danish Navy. I worked mainly with Java doing full stack development, which included both system integration towards different sensors and sub-systems and UI/UX development.

System Administrator at Elsevier (Atira A/S)

09/2013 - 07/2014

My work included the operation and maintenance of hardware and software, which included both local and cloud services running Microsoft Windows and different Linux OS. Database development, administration and installation on Oracle Database, Microsoft SQL Server and PostgreSQL. Customer software installation and upgrade which was either done manually or guided.

Student Helper for Network & Security at Aalborg University, Denmark.

Summer 2011

Worked on designing and analyze potential malicious network attacks on a deployed Intelligent Transport Systems in collaboration with Gatehouse Aalborg A/S.

Steffen Riber Thomsen

Network & Computer Engineer

Education

Master of Science (M.Sc.) in Network & Distributed Systems at Aalborg University:

2011 - 2013

Thesis: "Analysis and Improvement of Network Performance Measurement Procedures for Android Devices".

- Thesis focus on thorough analysis and testing of network performance measurement techniques tailored for use on mobile devices and cellular network.
- Throughout my master the main focus has been on measuring and analysis of Network Performance & Quality of Service. All the analysis has been done on empirical data gathered by a self-designed Android application named "NetMap".

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) in Computer Engineering with specialization in Communication

2008 - 2011

Systems at Aalborg University:

Thesis: "In-line Detection of Distributed Denial of Service Attacks on Core Networks".

- The thesis deals with analysis of DDoS attack and how one can prevent such attack.
- Throughout my bachelor I have worked with topic such as: Software and network design with focus on interaction between hardware, software and human.
- Embedded real-time systems on microcontrollers, very complex distributed system design and focus on robust communication.

Languages

Danish: Native fluencyEnglish: Fluent / Bilingual

Extracurricular activities and awards

"Internet Quality - more than bandwidth". - Based on work done throughout my master, where we developed the NetMap Application to measure and map the

Invited to participate and present at a conference by Collaborating Living Labs (COLL) named

2012

- Based on work done throughout my master, where we developed the NetMap Application to measure and map the Danish cellular network.
- The application gained a lot of media attention during the project, including several articles, a radio interview and a television interview (held by me). *All articles and media can be located at my Linkedin profile.*

Nominated for the Ing.dk (Ingeniøren) product award 2012 with the NetMap project. 2012 Accepted to present at IUCC2012 in Liverpool, UK with the IEEE article: "Location Assisted Vertical Handover Algorithm for QoS Optimization in End-to-End Connections". Best presentation award at 24th SEMCON at Aalborg University (12/22/2011) with the paper "High Level Link Adaption using Extended Network Knowledge and Prediction".

- Award price: 8000,- DKK

Granted 8800,- DKK from Network & Security at Aalborg University, Denmark, for research equipment for a multi semester project "Dynamic Application Migration".

2010